Jesse Hull - Front End Engineer

jsehull.com GitHub: jsehull jse.hull@gmail.com

OBJECTIVE

I have a non-traditional web development path with great life experience. I want to grow a company product/service with my continual learning and excellence and enjoy a fruitful atmosphere where teamwork and developer growth are cultivated. Let's talk.

FAMILIAR TECHNOLOGIES

- React, Next.js, jQuery, JavaScript
- CSS-in-JS, Emotion, Bootstrap, Sass
- Git, npm, yarn, Gulp, Grunt, Bower
- GitHub, BitBucket, Netlify, Firebase

- PHP, Laravel, Homestead, Codelgniter
- MySQL, NGINX, LAMP/WAMP
- GIMP 2, Figma, Paint!
- VS Code, vim, terminal, CLI

CURRENT ROLE

Freelance, Remote, CO

June 2020 - Present

- React Next.js Emotion CSS-in-JS
- godinyourgarden.com (React) Built/designed static site for independent author's book release
- jsehull.com (React) My personal portfolio and blog with links to various open source and code
- Open source contributions (OSS) Based on resources I have benefitted from
- Spare time I grow my technical abilities through various projects and online resources

WORK EXPERIENCE

GM, DUCTZ of Mid Michigan, Jackson, MI

- > JavaScript Bootstrap HTML
- Sales/marketing website updates
- Grew company culture, sales, and process
 BNI President for local chapter

Mar 2018- Feb 2019

- Oversaw employee growth and retention
- Developed partner relations

Junior Web Developer, Total Mortgage Services, Milford, CT

Sept 2016- Mar 2018

- JavaScript ¡Query Sass PHP Laravel MySQL
- Primary front-end developer for company website (construction and maintenance)
- Built responsive, mobile-first components and pages based on Photoshop designs
- Made the original site more responsive and mobile friendly before new site build
- Laid out vision for our CMO to inspire and drive the creation of our new company website
- Wrote and debugged clean and organized code, refactoring as needed
- Sent emails and form data through front and backend validation (AJAX/POST)

Web Developer, DUCTZ of Mid Michigan, Remote, CT

June 2016- Sept 2016

- > JavaScript Bootstrap HTML BitBucket
- New site increased sales 80%
- Created static website with original content for remote client
- Built for mobile first with responsive layout and ease of use to drive user engagement
- Leveraged HTML5 components to skip basic design decisions and allow for faster completion
- Authored all content for the website (descriptions, images, backgrounds, etc)

EDUCATION

University of Wisconsin-Milwaukee (UWM), Milwaukee, WI Economics. B.A.

Graduated 2011

• Economics Mentoring Program Internship